（会員）
どうぞ お客様 こちらですわ
This way, madam.
（夢子(ゆめこ)）あら
Oh, my.
（芽亜里(めあり)）
はっ 蛇喰(じゃばみ)夢子！ どうして…
Yumeko Jabami? Why?
う… ダメだ 集中しないと
No, I need to concentrate.
（百合子(ゆりこ)）あらあら
Oh, my. Don't look so upset.
そんな怖い顔 なさらないで
Let's enjoy our gambling.
せっかくのギャンブル
楽しみましょう
（芽亜里）
クソッ 出目を予測するだけの
丁半ばくちのようなもの
Damn it.
All have to do is guess the right numbers.
Skill has nothing to do with it.
技術は関係ない
なのに なぜ
ここまで偏る？
Why are the results
so tilted in her favor?
私が
よほどの不運でなければ
If I'm not on one hell of an unlucky
streak, the only possibility is...
考えられるのは…
イカサマ！
she's cheating.
（百合子）ウフッ
I don't know how, but she's probably
slowly setting something up.
（芽亜里）
方法は分からない
だが 恐らくジワジワと
何かを仕掛けられている
それなら…
Which means...
Thirty-two chips.
I'm betting my whole stack!
32枚 残り全部 賭ける！
Oh, my. Going on the offensive, huh?
おや 勝負にきましたね
結構ですわ
Very well.
（熊楠(くまぐす)）両者 出そろいました
Both players are ready.
では 剣10本 入ります
Ten swords. Beginning.
さあ 張った 張った！
Lay your bets!
Ten, nine, eight...
10… ９… ８…
- She fell for it. All I have to do...
- ...seven, six, five, four, three, two...
（芽亜里）
掛かった！ あとは…
（熊楠）
６… ５… ４… ３… ２…
なるほど
I see.
I've bet on five spots, six chips apiece.
（芽亜里）
５か所に６枚 集中ベット
一発で勝負を決めて
イカサマの隙を与えない
I'll end the game
so she won't have a chance to cheat.
Time's up. Bets are laid.
（熊楠）
それまで！
賭け方 出そろいました
では 参ります
Here we go.
Two, four, eight, 16, 22.
I just need one, please.
（芽亜里）
２ ４ ８ 16 22
１つでいい 当たってくれ
（熊楠）勝負！
Revealing the board.
Twenty-two. Mary got it right!
（鈴井(すずい)）
22！ 早乙女(さおとめ)の当たりだ！
あらあら あなたの当たりですわね
Oh, my. You picked the right spot.
ただし
But...
判定は“死”ですけれど
the judgment is death.
はあ！ あっ ああ…
ご愁傷さま
Too bad.
（鈴井）
何だ 判定？
What? The judgment? Didn't Mary win?
早乙女が勝ったんじゃないのか？
（熊楠）22
Twenty-two. Since the blade is embedded
in the board, the judgment is death.
刃が刺さっているため
判定は“死”
６枚ベットの早乙女様は
Saotome bet six chips.
She loses 30 times that.
30倍 180枚のマイナスで
1800万円
One hundred eighty chips,
or 18 million yen.
百合子様のチップを合わせて
Adding in Yuriko's chips, she loses
with a total of minus 49.6 million chips.
合計4960万円のマイナスで
決着です
（百合子）
お疲れさまでした 早乙女さん
Good game, Mary.
回収方法は
追って お知らせしますわ
I'll tell you later
how I intend to collect.
誰か 外へ お連れして
Someone take her outside.
もう 用済みですから
I'm done with her.
うわ〜！
（熊楠）早乙女様！
- You're bothering the other customers.
- Don't touch me!
ほかのお客様の
ご迷惑になりますので…
（芽亜里）触るな！
（芽亜里）
上納金を払おうと思えば払えた
I could've paid the money if I wanted to.
でも それじゃ
私が失った地位は戻ってこない
But I couldn't get
the position I lost back.
こんな勝負 するんじゃなかった
I never should've played this game.
元の地位を取り戻すなんて
夢を見なければ…
I should've never dreamed
of taking back my old position.
いや そんなことより
No, more than that,
蛇喰夢子
it was a mistake to ever get involved
with Yumeko Jabami.
この女と関わったのが
間違いだった
〜
Mary was in bad enough shape
that she challenged her to a formal match?
早乙女…
公式戦を挑むほど
追い詰められていたのか
（夢子）
鈴井さん 公式戦というのは？
Ryota, what's a formal match?
（鈴井）あっ うん
Right.
A formal match
is the one right given to a house pet.
公式戦というのは
家畜に与えられた唯一の権利なんだ
家畜は一度だけ 誰にでも
ギャンブルを挑む権利がある
A pet has the right to challenge
anyone to a match once.
賭け金が常識の範囲内なら
それを拒むことは許されない
If the betting amount is reasonable,
you're not allowed to refuse.
しかも 慣例的に生徒会役員は
It's traditional for members
of the student council to accept them
公式戦を
青天井で受けることになってる
with no upper betting limit.
だから 時々 家畜から
一発逆転を狙った大勝負が
Sometimes, the house pets
will challenge them for one big game.
挑まれたりするんだ
それを今 早乙女さんが？
And Mary just did that?
（百合子）そういうことです
That's right.
SLIT-EYED WOMAN
蛇喰夢子さんですわね？
Yumeko Jabami, right?
ようこそ 伝統文化研究会へ
Welcome
to the Traditional Culture Research Club.
私 生徒会役員 兼
I'm a member of the student council,
as well as the president of the club.
当研究会の会長を
務めております—
西洞院(にしのとういん)百合子と申します
My name is Yuriko Nishinotoin.
Hello.
（夢子）はじめまして
（百合子）ご用向きは？
What brings you here?
I guess I don't need to ask, do I?
なんて 聞くまでもないですわね
どうでしょう わたくしと一戦
Why not play a game with me?
我が研究会 オリジナルギャンブル
“生か死か”で
It's an original gambling game
my club came up with, Life or Death.
That sounds like lots of fun! I'd love to.
面白そうですね
ぜひ お願いします
（夢子）ウフフッ
（鈴井）あっ はあ…
（百合子）生か死か
Life or Death.
First, ten small sword pieces
are put into a pot.
まず つぼに剣の形を模した駒を
10本入れて 盤に振ります
There are 30 spots on the board
with numbers.
盤には番号を付した穴が
30か所 開いておりまして
剣がどの穴に刺さるか予想して
チップを賭けます
You bet your chips
where you think the swords will fall.
簡単に言えば
ルーレットや丁半ばくちのように
It's very similar to roulette
or Japanese Cho-Han gambling.
出目を予想するゲームですわ
You try to guess the right number.
ただし 生か死かの面白いところは
But what makes Life or Death interesting
is that if the sword comes up blade-first,
剣が上向きで刺さったときは
判定が“生”となり 倍率30倍
it's life,
and the return is multiplied by 30.
下向きで刺さったときは
If it lands hilt-first, it's death,
and the result is minus 30.
判定が“死”となり
マイナス30倍
つまり 相手に
30倍 支払うことになりますわ
In other words, you pay your opponent
30 times the amount.
賭け方には 決まりがありまして
There are rules for betting.
１回ごとに あらかじめ
Each round both players decide
how many chips they're going to bet.
その勝負で賭けるチップを
両者の合意で決めます
振り子が つぼを振ってから
10秒の間に
The judge shakes the pot for ten seconds.
Meanwhile, you put chips on the board.
チップを賭けたい目に置きます
そうして どちらかのチップが
ゼロになったとき
And when one person runs out of chips,
その差額をもって
決勝金額といたします
the difference between both sides
becomes the amount won.
では 賭け金を決めましょう
Let's decide on the amount to bet.
It would be boring to bet too little.
あまり小さい金額では
興ざめですが…
Okay, let's do 40 million yen.
はい ４千万円でやりましょう
いいでしょう
Very well.
では 最初に賭けるチップは
どうしましょう 夢子さん
So, Yumeko, what chips shall we bet first?
Let's see. I guess I'll start
by getting a feel for it. Ten chips.
（夢子）そうですね
では 様子見で… 10枚
（百合子）いいでしょう
Very well.
（熊楠）両者 出そろいました
Both players are ready.
では 剣10本 入ります
Ten swords. Beginning.
さあ 張った 張った！
Lay your bets!
10… ９… ８… ７… ６…
Ten, nine, eight, seven...
（熊楠）５… ４…
（夢子）う〜ん
- ...six, five, four, three, two...
- I've decided.
（熊楠）３… ２… １…
（夢子）うん 決めました
...one, zero.
ゼロ そこまで！
Time's up.
賭け方 出そろいました
Bets are laid.
（百合子）
フフッ 直前まで
考えていらっしゃったようですが
You seemed to be thinking
until the last second.
何か意図でも おありなのですか？
Do you have some plan?
ええ そのつぼ 僅かに
裾広がりになってますよね
Yes. That pot is slightly wider
at the top than the bottom.
とすると 物理的に
It's more likely that the swords will land
on the small numbers in the center.
恐らく真ん中の若い番号に
刺さる可能性が高い
判定が生にせよ死にせよ
Whether I get life or death, if I don't
get the number right, it's boring.
当たらなければ
つまらないですよね
私 あまり気が長いほうでは
ありませんので
I'm not a very patient girl.
ウフフ
それが
仇(あだ)にならないことを
I pray that does not come back
to haunt you.
お祈りいたしますわ
では 参ります
Here we go. Revealing the board.
勝負！
Seventeen, life.
17の生
Thirty, death.
30の死
あっ！
（鈴井）
夢子は… 外れか
Yumeko didn't get one right.
西洞院さんは？
Nishinotoin got...
あっ 危ない
That was close. She was one off.
あと１つ ずれてたら
当たりだった
Every chip on life is 30 million yen.
１枚当てれば３千万だぞ！
（熊楠）
両者 外れましたので
チップの移動はありません
Since both players won nothing,
no chips will change hands.
惜しい 惜しい
さあ 次にいきましょう
How close.
Let's move on to the next round.
Yumeko, I can't watch this. You can't
gamble with this stupid amount of money.
夢子 見てらんないよ
こんなバカな金額のギャンブル
やっぱりやめ…
鈴井さん
Ryota, you don't need to worry.
そんなに心配なさらなくても
大丈夫ですよ
この程度のお金
惜しくもありません
This tiny amount of money
is meaningless to me.
それに チップの移動が
激しいからこそ
And the speed at which chips change hands
is what makes this game interesting.
このギャンブルは面白い
途中でやめるなんて
もったいないです
It would be a waste to stop now.
（百合子）
鈴井さんとおっしゃいましたか？
- Ryota, was it?
- Yes.
は… はい
ただ１回のつぼ振りで
The feeling
of unimaginable amounts of money
予想を超えた大金が動くこの感覚
moving around
with a single shake of a pot...
あなたも一度味わえば
分かると思いますわ
If you tasted it once, you'd understand.
Right, Yumeko?
ねえ 夢子さん
ええ 病みつきに
なってしまいそうです
Yes. I can see myself getting addicted.
（夢子）ただ 西洞院さん
（百合子）うん？
But, Nishinotoin,
あなたのやり方は最低ですけど
the way you're playing is terrible.
（鈴井）あっ！
（熊楠）あっ！
失礼 今 何と？
I'm sorry, what was that?
Did you not hear me?
I said you're terrible.
聞こえませんでしたか？
あなたは最低だと申し上げたのです
先ほどの早乙女さんとの公式戦
That official match with Mary...
どうせ あなたのほうから
You're the one
who suggested this game, right?
このギャンブルを
持ちかけたのでしょう？
早乙女さんは
ご自身の名誉を回復するために
I think Mary challenged you to restore
her honor, but if that's all she wanted,
挑まれたのだと思いますが
それだけなら こんな損害が
ばく大になりうるギャンブルを
she didn't need to play a game
with such huge potential losses.
する必要はありませんからね
弱った人間に僅かな希望を与え
更なる絶望へとたたき込む
Giving someone in a bad spot hope,
then sending them into deeper despair...
ヤミ金融などと同じです
It's the same as being sleazy loan broker.
I don't know how good a gambler you are,
but you're the worst kind of human being.
あなたはギャンブルの強さは
どうか知りませんけど
人間としては下の下
クソのようなものですね
- You're a piece of shit, aren't you?
- How rude! Yuriko, let's kick her out!
ぶ… 無礼な！
百合子様！ この女 たたき出し…
ああ！
はあ…
（百合子）どうしたのですか？
What's wrong, Kumagusu?
熊楠さん
（熊楠）うっ… はっ！
ちょっとした軽口ではないですか
We're just bantering a little.
あっ はい
- Of course.
- It's a shame, though.
（夢子）
ああ それにしても残念でした
I was sure I'd see two, four, and ten.
But it didn't work that way.
きっと ２ ４ 10 がくると
思ってたのに
うまくいかないものですね
２ ４ 10？
Two, four, ten?
I love word games.
私 言葉遊びが大好きなんですよ
西洞院ってお名前
In Japanese,
the name Nishinotoin can be read "2410in."
２(に) ４(し) の 10(とう) in
って読めるでしょう？
Are you not superstitious?
そういう験は
担がれないんですか？
あまり人の名前で
Would you not play games with my name?
遊ばないで
いただけますか？
西洞院は
平安京にゆえんを持つ
Nishinotoin is a name stretching back
to the earliest days of Japan.
由緒正しい名前です
（夢子）しかも！
If you count them as even numbers,
偶数で数えると
間の６と８が抜けてるんですよ
the six and eight in the middle
are missing.
間が抜けてる… フフフ
There's an empty space between them.
マヌケな名前ってことですね
アハハ〜 ああ ケッサク！
An empty space just like the empty space
in your head. That's hilarious!
Right, Ryota?
（夢子）ねっ 鈴井さん
（鈴井）ええ？
Would you knock it off?
き… 貴様！ いいかげんに…
（百合子）フフッ フフフフ…
面白い
Interesting.
生徒会長のおっしゃるとおり
Just like
what the student council president said,
あなた 本当に面白い
you really are interesting.
まあ そんなに褒めていただくと
何だか こそばゆいですね
When you compliment me,
it makes me feel all tingly.
ハア〜
さあ 続けましょう
Let's continue. How much will you bet?
賭け金は いくらになさいます？
残り全部 40枚で
All I have left. 40 chips.
よい覚悟ですわね
You've got quite a bit of resolve, huh?
Kumagusu?
（百合子）熊楠さん
（熊楠）あ…
りょ… 両者 出そろいました
Both players are ready.
では 剣10本 入ります
Ten swords. Beginning!
さあ 張った 張った！
10…
Lay your bets! Ten...
このまま普通に勝っても
It wouldn't be good for my mental state
to just win normally, would it?
精神衛生上
よろしくありませんわね
ストレスは美容の大敵ですから
Stress is the enemy of beauty.
生か死か
Life or death. I'll kill you, literally.
文字どおり 殺して差し上げます
（鈴井）
５枚 ８か所！
Five chips on eight spots.
If she wanted to take Yumeko down,
there'd be no need to bet all five.
夢子のチップをゼロ以下にするなら
５枚も賭ける必要はない
間違いなく怒ってる
She's definitely crazy.
I knew provoking her was a mistake.
やっぱり挑発は余計だった
（熊楠）２… １… ゼ…
...two, one, zer--
あっ！
西洞院さん
Nishinotoin, if you were offended
by what I said, I apologize.
先ほどの言葉
お気に障ったのなら謝ります
全部 始めから
ここに賭けるための出任せですので
It was all lies I told
to bring us to this point.
許してくださいね
Please forgive me.
（百合子）あっ！
ど… どうして？
- Why?
- Why? Because you're cheating.
どうしてって あなたが
イカサマをしているからですよ
（熊楠･百合子）はっ！
Cheating?
イカサマ？
ええ 振り子のあの方の右手を
見てください
Yes. Look at the judge's right hand.
一見 ほくろのようなものが
ありますでしょう？
You see what looks like moles, right?
（鈴井）あっ 確かに
That's right.
（夢子）
これと同じものが
I saw the same thing on the girl
who brought us in here.
この部屋に案内してくださった方
にもありました
（鈴井）
どういうこと？
- What does that mean?
- Those moles are artificial.
つまり あのほくろは人為的なもの
きっとピアスでしょう
Piercings, I'm sure.
このイカサマのためだけに
You're piercing your club members' hands
just for the sake of this trick.
会員の手に
ピアスを通すなんて ウフッ
西洞院さん
Nishinotoin, that's really wonderful.
あなた とっても
すてきなことをしますね
I imagine every single sword
has a magnet in it.
恐らく剣の中に１本だけ
磁石を仕込んであるんでしょう
If you put a magnetic field
on the piercings,
振り子の手のピアスに
磁気を持たせておけば
you can fix the sword in a certain spot.
つぼの外から剣を固定できます
Then you just slide your hand
along the pot like this,
あとは こう…
つぼの側面に手を滑らせれば
晴れて目的の場所 任意の向きに
剣を落とせるというわけです
and you can send the sword
wherever you like.
そんなことを!?
Wait. You're telling me you provoked her
to make sure she cheated this round?
さっきの挑発は この回で
確実にイカサマさせるための…
（百合子）待ちなさい！
Wait.
あなたが この場所に来てから
I haven't gotten a single spot right
since you came here.
わたくしは １回も
剣の位置を当てていません
先の場でも あなたのお友達は
つぼを振ってから賭けたのです
Your friend only bet in the last game
while the pot was being shaken.
わたくしが関与する余地など
ないではありませんか！
There's no way I could've cheated!
（夢子）
このイカサマの
よく出来ているところは
What makes this cheat so wonderful
100パーセント
勝てるわけではないということです
is that you can't win
100 percent of the time.
It takes a lot of control for the judge
to send the sword to the right spot.
振り子が 持ち手で
狙った穴に剣を落とすには
かなりのコントロールが
必要でしょう
他の剣が 穴を
塞いでしまうこともあるでしょうし
Another sword might block it.
何より１本しか操作できないので
あとの出目は運任せ
Since you can only control one sword,
the others are left to luck.
実際の勝率は 大した数字に
ならないのではないですか？
I'd imagine your actual win ratio
isn't that high, is it?
That's why Mary couldn't catch you.
The cheating isn't a sure thing.
だからこそ早乙女さんも
これを見抜けなかった
不確実なイカサマ
ですが あなたには
それで十分だった
But that was enough for you.
You're the president
of the Traditional Culture Research Club
伝統文化研究会会長で
生徒会役員でもあるあなたは
and a member of the student council.
さぞや大金を持って
鉄火場に臨んでいるのでしょうね
You've got plenty of money when you play.
ならば１回１回のギャンブルに
確実な勝利などいらず
You don't need to win every match.
相手より少し有利であればいい
You just need to win a little more
than your opponents.
何十回 何百回と 賭場で
繰り返されるギャンブルの中で
Over the course of hundreds of games,
you can win stable earnings.
安定して
プラスを稼ぎだすことができる
このイカサマの肝は
トリックではなく あなたの資金力
The core of this trick isn't the trick
itself, it's how much money you have.
きっとあなたは 数千万程度のお金
失っても何とも思わない
A few million yen is nothing to you.
ですが それでは
対等なギャンブルとは言えません
But that's not a fair game.
私は全財産を賭けているのに
不公平です ウフッ
I'm betting my entire fortune.
It's not fair.
くっ…
（夢子）同じ痛みを感じましょう
Let's feel the same pain.
私のベットは40枚
My bet is 40 chips.
もし判定が“生”で的中したら
あなたの負け分は…
If I get the life, your loss will be
（夢子）21億７千万円！
2.17 billion yen.
ウフフフ
たった一度で
これだけ失うかもしれない
You may lose all that in a single round.
まさに生か死か
It's truly life or death, isn't it?
Come on.
さあ さあ さあ さあ！
さあ〜！
賭け狂いましょう！
Let's get our gamble freak on!
（百合子）ハア ハア ハア ハア
Come on, let's finish it!
ほら 決着を！
さあ つぼを開いてください！
Open the pot!
（熊楠）くっ…
ゆっ 百合子様！
Nishinotoin!
（百合子）
負ければ 21億７千万円
If I lose, I lose 2.17 billion yen.
I can't afford to lose that much money.
そんな大金 わたくしでも
左から右へ動かせるわけはない
それなら プールしてある
伝文研の上納金を…
I'd have to take all the funds
in the club's pool.
でも それを維持できなければ
生徒会役員の地位が…
But if I can't maintain that,
I lose my seat on the student council.
The club can only exist
because I'm on the council.
わたくしが役員であればこそ
会も存続できるし
会の子たちが
家畜になることも防げる
That's how I keep the girls
from being house pets.
そうでなければ 全てが崩壊する
If I lose that, I lose everything.
破滅だ！
I'm ruined. I have to talk her down.
If I do it before she opens the pot...
じ… 示談するしかない
つぼを開く前なら まだ…
ゆ… 夢子さん
Yumeko.
（鈴井）あっ…
（夢子）あっ
（綺羅莉(きらり)）お邪魔するわね
Excuse me.
President? Why?
か… 会長 どうして！
This looks fun.
なかなか面白いことに
なってるみたいね
ハッ
賭けてる金額も大きいみたいだし
It looks like you're betting a lot.
こんなときは
トラブルが起きがちだからね
At times like this, trouble is likely
to occur. I'll be an observer.
私が見届け人になってあげる
There's no need for you to.
I can handle this myself.
か… 会長の手を
煩わせるまでもありません
このぐらいのこと
わたくしのほうで…
うっ うう…
いいから黙って開けよ
Just shut up and play.
（るな）
ニャッハハ 百合子ちゃん
真っ青だけど大丈夫？
You're dead pale, Yuriko. Are you okay?
百合子様…
Nishinotoin.
はあ
うん…
ぐっ… では 参ります 勝負！
Here we go. Revealing the board.
うわ！
Death on ten and life on seven!
10の死と７の生
Seven. I just bet there randomly.
（百合子）
７… わたくしが適当に賭けた場所
いや それよりも
No, more importantly,
it didn't land on 24?
24に刺さってない ですって？
Nishinotoin bet five chips on life,
so she has 195 chips in total.
（熊楠）
百合子様 判定“生”で
５枚的中ですので
チップは合計195枚
蛇喰様 マイナス115枚
Jabami has minus 115 chips.
Yuriko wins with 310 million yen.
百合子様
３億１千万円の勝ちで決着です
（鈴井）
う… うそだろ…
夢子が負けた？
Impossible. Yumeko lost?
ふ〜ん
まさか勝ってしまうとまでは
思わなかったわ
I didn't think you'd actually win.
百合子 あなた
なかなか強運じゃない
Yuriko, you've got some good luck.
I'm impressed.
見直したわ
But, you, I'm disappointed in you.
それに比べて
あなたは残念だったわね
You tried so hard
and lost to a lucky punch.
頑張ったのに
こんなラッキーパンチに
負けてしまって
穴熊(あなぐま)でしょうか…
Was it a badger? You got me there.
これは参りましたね
さあ どうかしら？
I couldn't say.
（るな）
ニャッ ハハハ アハハハ…
（夢子）穴熊っていうのは
A badger was a trick once used
in Japanese Cho-Han gambling.
昔 丁半ばくちで用いられた
イカサマなんです
このイカサマ まず賭場の床に
小さな穴を開けておくんです
First, you put a small hole in the floor.
その上で ばくちをするのですが
The gambling's done on top of it.
Since a white cloth is put down,
it's hard to see.
白布を敷いているので
一見 分かりません
日本家屋には
床下にスペースがありますよね
Japanese houses have space
under the floors, right?
この床下にイカサマ師が潜みます
The cheater hides under the floorboards.
そのイカサマ師は
He uses candlelight or something else
ろうそくの火などで白布を透かして
サイコロの目を確認し
to see through the floor
and look at the dice.
出目によっては
針をサイコロ目がけて突き刺します
And depending on what they are,
pokes at them with a needle,
そうして
胴元の有利なものに変えてしまう
changing them to something
that benefits the house.
恐らく生徒会長は
I bet the student council president used
magnets to make someone do the same thing.
今回 磁石を使って
それと同じことをやらせた
24に入っていた剣を
She used the magnets
to knock the sword out of spot 24.
磁石の反発で
下から弾き飛ばしたんです
西洞院さんの様子から考えると
彼女はこれを知らされていなかった
From the look on Nishinotoin's face,
she wasn't told.
１本当てたのは偶然
It was coincidence,
pure luck, that she won.
まさに強運というわけですね
But you can only do that if you have space
under the floor, like a Japanese building.
（鈴井）
でもさ それは日本家屋みたいに
床下にスペースがある場合だろ？
You can just make a space above the room.
You just build the room to accommodate it.
（夢子）
スペースなら この部屋の上に
作ればいいじゃないですか
そういう建築にすればいい
いえ もしかすると
No, perhaps the president put it in
just for that game.
会長があのギャンブルのためだけに
改築させたのかも
まっ… まさか
Don't tell me...
（夢子）
ああ… そうだったら
どんなにいいでしょう
How wonderful that would be.
普通はそんなこと
発想の範ちゅうにはないし
Normally, you wouldn't think of that.
たとえ思いついてもやりません
Even if you did, you wouldn't actually
do it. Only a madwoman would.
やるのは狂っている人だけ
想像以上です！
この学園… いえ 生徒会長は！
This academy, no,
the student council president,
is beyond what I imagined.
うん 決めました
I've decided.
私 生徒会長とギャンブルしたい！
I want to gamble
with the student council president.
ああ…
Mittens!
（生徒たち）
ミ〜ケ ミ〜ケ ミ〜ケ…
BOTTOM-FEEDER 0001 MITTENS
ウフフ
（生徒Ａ）蛇喰さん
（夢子）あっ？
Jabami.
I heard you gambled
with the student council yesterday.
（生徒Ａ）
聞いたよ 昨日
生徒会とギャンブルしたって
Yes, but I lost.
はい でも 負けちゃいました
（生徒Ｃ）うん それも聞いた
Yeah, I heard that too.
（生徒Ａ）それでね 私たち…
And so, we...
まあ 皆さん ご心配ありが…
Oh, you're all worried--
（３人）キャハハハ！
What are you talking about, house pet?
We're here to laugh at you!
（生徒Ｂ）何 言っちゃってんの！
家畜の分際(ぶんざい)で！
笑いに来たんだって！
Nobody's worried about you, Mittens.
（生徒Ｃ）
ミケの心配なんて
誰もしないっつうの！
（生徒Ａ）
負け猫根性が感染しちゃうじゃん！
Your loser cat genes might rub off on us.
（３人）ギャハハハ
（夢子）なるほど
I see. So, female house pets are Mittens.
女子の家畜はミケ
負け猫というわけですね
Loser cats.
猫だなんて
かわいいじゃありませんか
Cats are cute, though, right?
（３人）はあ？
（夢子）にゃん にゃん
Meow, meow. I'm a losing cat
with a gambling addiction.
ギャンブル中毒の負け猫だにゃん
うっかり生徒会に負けちゃって
３億も借金しちゃったにゃん
I lost to the student council,
and now I have 300 million yen in debt.
どうやって取り返そうかにゃ〜
How should I get it back, huh?
I want to gamble more.
もっともっと
ギャンブルしたいにゃ〜
誰かパトロンに
なってくれないかにゃ〜
Would anybody like to be my patron?
（生徒Ｂ）な… 何なの こいつ！
What's with her?
（生徒Ｃ）
あ… 頭 おかしいんじゃないの？
- She's crazy.
- Let's go.
（生徒Ａ）い… 行こう！
（鈴井）ゆ… 夢子！
Yumeko.
What are you doing?
な… 何やってんだ！
フフッ
冗談の通じない方たちですね
They've got no sense of humor, huh?
ねっ 鈴井にゃん
- Right, Ryota?
- I get it.
わ… 分かったから
I could get into this.
（夢子）
あら 何だか
ハマってしまいそうです
尻尾も
付けたほうがいいでしょうか？
- Should I wear a tail?
- Stop it.
（鈴井）よしなさいって
Good morning, everyone.
（清華(さやか)）
おはようございます 皆さん
Morning.
（るな）おっはよ〜
百合子ちゃん 来ないね〜
Yuriko's not here, is she?
She couldn't show up after that failure.
（豆生田(まにゅうだ)）
ぶざまな失態をさらしておいて
ノコノコと顔は出せまい
ニャッハハ！
せっかく勝ったのに〜
But she won, though.
おはよう 清華
Good morning, Sayaka.
（清華）おはようございます 会長
Good morning, Student Council President.
These are the plans for Yumeko Jabami
and Mary Saotome.
こちら 蛇喰夢子 早乙女芽亜里
両名の計画表です
LIFE PLANS - YUMEKO
〜
- We call it the Debt Swap Game.
- Shut up!
（清華）
借金つけかえゲーム！
（木渡(きわたり)）
お前 ミケになったんだってな
- I heard you're Mittens now.
- The only choice here is to shoot!
（妄(みだり)）
誰がどう考えたって 撃つ 一択！
Call. One Tsubomi chip.
This feeling, it's wonderful.
（夢子）
この感覚… たまらない
EPISODE 4:
THE GIRL WHO BECAME A HOUSE PET